aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Wh- what's...
이, 이건!?
Destroy the Ultimate Weapon
최종병기를 파괴하라
Space Ascetic Death Pulse Seijin
Appears
우주 선인 데스펄스 성인 등장
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!
Blizzard Typhoon!
블리자드 타이푼!
No good! It's not stopping!
무리야! 멈출 수 없어!
In this rate, the village will be demolished!
이대로라면 마을은 괴멸합니다!
Don't give up!
포기하지마!
Believe in the power that Brave Seijin gave us!
브레이브 성인이 우리에게 내려준 힘을 믿는거다!
Kai! Shin! Yoku!
카이! 신! 요쿠!
G- guys!
얘, 얘들아!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체
(重連合體)
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온
They combined!
합체하다니!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!
Armor Buster!
아머 버스터!
En!
엔!
-What about the tidal wave?
-Don't worry.
- 해일은?
- 안심해
What's that?
저건!?
What do you think? Do you like this stand-up food store?
어때? 이 포장마차(立ち食い) 꽤 맛있지 않냐?
Huh? Do you hate noodles?
얼레, 국수 싫어하냐?
No.
아니
Then why aren't you eating?
근데 왜 안먹냐?
One have to sit down to eat.
식사는 앉아서 하는 거야
I must not eat when I'm standing.
서서 먹을 순 없어
Well, I guess that's an extreme way of keeping disciplines.
풍기의 모범을 보여주는구만, 정말
Then I will!
그럼, 할 수 없이 내가…
Anyway, do you feel alright now...
그건 그렇고, 몸은 이제 괜찮…
Sorry for asking.
은 것 같군
Looking at that appetite makes me think we didn't even have a battle.
저 식욕을 보고 있자니 좀전까지의 싸움이 거짓말 같아요
I still can't believe this.
난 아직 믿기지 않아
We stopped that gigantic tidal wave!
그 엄청난 파도를 우리가 막았다니 말야
We did it!
우리들이!
It wouldn't have been possible if we didn't get along pretty well.
우리들 3명의 호흡이 왠만큼 맞지 않았다면 불가능했을 참이었다
That would mean, you need three people to get one person's work done.
즉, 3명이 모여야 한사람 몫을 한다는 거구만
What?
뭐야?
That must be great! I want to combine with someone too!
야~ 좋겠다! 나도 누구랑 합체하고 싶은데~
En!
엔!
Calm down. It seems that he isn't trying to offend us.
진정하세요, 나쁜 뜻은 없는 것 같으니까요
Hurry up, En.
서둘러라, 엔
Huh?
음?
We can still make it for the third class of the day.
지금이라면 아직 3교시 수업에 늦지 않아
School?!
학교!?
A student is expected to attend school.
학생이 학교에 등교하는 것은 당연한 것
Isn't it alright? One day shouldn't be so...
상관 없잖냐? 오늘 하루 정도는…
Don't say. 4 or 5
Captain!
선장님!
What the-?! Avoid right now!
이런, 전속 회피!
We can't make it! We're being pulled!
틀렸습니다!
빨려 들어갑니다!
Wh- what's that?!
뭐, 뭐지 저건!?
That must have something to do with the gigantic tidal wave.
거대 해일의 원인과 뭔가 관련이 있을지도 몰라
Investigate carefully.
주의해서 조사해라
Looking at this, we shouldn't expect a survivor.
이 상태로 봐선 생존자는 기대할 수 없겠군요
A person!
사람이 있어!
I'll go ask where hospital is!
병원이 있는 곳을 물어보고 오겠습니다
-Is he awake now?
-Get a grip, mister!
- 정신이 들은건가?
- 정신차려, 이봐!
-He's shocked.
-Shocked?
- 쇼크 상태다
- 쇼크 상태?
With one more strong impact... Maybe...
한번 더 강한 충격을 받으면 원래대로…
Kai! Shin!
카이! 신!
Who did that?!
대체 누구에게 당한거지?
H- h- help me!
사, 살려줘!
What the heck happened?
대체 무슨 일이 있었던 거지!?
Bird... a bird...
새… 새…
What about a bird? What happened in the sea?!
새가 어쨌다는 거야!? 바다에서 무슨 일이 있었던 거냐고!?
Why did the ship sink?
배는 왜 침몰한 거냐!?
Remember why!
생각해 내란 말야!
A... a top...
패, 팽이가…
Top?
팽이?
A big top...
거, 거대한 팽이가…
The ship is sinking!
배가 침몰한다!
Get down!
엎드려!
An alien?!
우주인!?
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Turbo Kai!
터보 카이
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Armor Shin!
아머 신
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Wing Yoku!
윙 요쿠
Dag Armor! Dag Wing! Let's combine!
다그 아머! 다그 윙! 합체다!
No need for that!
그럴 필요 없어!
Dag Armor?!
다그 아머!?
I am enough for that one guy!
저런 녀석 정도는 나 혼자서도 충분하다구!
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Blizzard Typhoon!
블리자드 타이푼!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Like bats, there are certain birds that navigates using the sound waves they emitted, like using a radar.
박쥐와 마찬가지로 새 중에는 스스로 발산하는 음파로 일종의 레이더 비행을 하는 종류가 있습니다
I think the reason behind the reaction of birds when the top appeared is that
팽이가 출현했을 때 일어난 새의 이상 현상은 팽이를 조종하는 우주인의 음파 또는 전자파 같은 것이
sound waves or electromagnetic of the alien controlling the top is blocking and disturbing the birds' radar-like activities.
이러한 새의 레이더 기능을 봉쇄, 교란시키기 때문이라고 생각됩니다
Why didn't you call me?!
왜 날 안 부른 거냐!?
Is your supplementary class over?
보충수업은 끝났나, 엔?
I don't know if it was a gigantic top or lithosphere melting, but wasn't three of you enough?!
거대한 팽이인지 지각 융용인지 모르겠지만 셋이나 몰려갔으면서 대체 뭘 한 거냐!?
What?
뭐라고?
Shouldn't three people combined at least worth one?
합체해도 역시 한사람 몫은 못 하는 거냐?
En!
엔!
Stop, Shin!
기다려, 신!
You can't deal with that top by yourself.
그 팽이는 너 혼자 쓰러뜨릴 정도로 만만하지 않아
Are you commanding me?
나한테 명령하는 거냐?
What?
뭐야?
When did you ever become the leader of Dagwon?!
언제부터 네놈이 다그온의 리더가 된 거냐!?
That's right! The leader is me, right here!
맞아! 리더는 바로 나라구!
Don't complicate the story!
이야기를 복잡하게 만들지 마세요!
When we combine, Yoku and I are nothing more than your hands and feet!
합체를 하면, 나와 요쿠는 너의 수족에 지나지 않아!
That is wrong. To combine is to make three body to one.
그건 아니야! 합체는 삼신일체(三身日體)
We need Yoku's knowledge and your power!
요쿠의 지식과 너의 힘이 필요하단 말이다!
I don't want to hear your theories!
너의 이론 따윈 듣기 싫다구!
Shin!
신!
Kai!
카이!
I will do as I please.
난 나 좋을대로 하겠다
What's this?
이건?
What the?!
아니!?
Breast Motor Cannon!
브레스트 모터 캐논!
-En!
-Is it Shin? Where are you?
-엔!
-신이냐? 지금 어디 있어!?
Probably in front of your eyes!
아마 너희들 눈 앞일 거다
You... did you...?!
너… 설마 너!?
Shin!
신!
You idiot! Get out of there!
바보자식, 탈출하라구!
If I could, I would have already done it!
할 수 있었으면 벌써 했겠다!
Shin!
신!
En! I'm going to stop the top from spinning with Dag Turbo.
엔, 다그 터보로 팽이의 회전을 정지시킬게
While I'm doing that, rescue Shin!
그 사이에 넌 신을 구출해
Don't do it! It's too dangerous!
그만둬! 위험하다구!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Wing!
다그 윙
Dag Wing, requesting for cover!
다그 윙, 엄호를 부탁한다
Roger!
라져!
Blizzard Typhoon!
블리자드 타이푼!
Kai!
카이!
En!
엔!
Fire Bird!
파이어 버드!
En!
엔!
Hurry up!
서둘러!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Armor!
다그 아머
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체
(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
Dag Armor...
다그 아머!
That was rash!
터무니 없는 짓을 하고 말야
Can you combine with that body?
그 몸으로 합체할 수 있겠냐?
I'll entrust my life to you!
내 목숨을 네게 맡기겠다!
-Shin!
-Kai!
- 신!
- 카이!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체
(重連合體)
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온
Jet Fire Storm!
제트 파이어 스톰!
Liner Tackle!
라이너 태클!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!
This is what youth is!
이런게 바로 청춘이지
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
tomaru koto nai MELODY
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
tooku kirameita
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
My natural enemy, Ijuuin Vice Principal.
내 천적 이쥬인 교감
Don't slant your eyes for being late a bit!
조금 지각한 걸 가지고 눈꼬리 세우지 말라구요!
What?! An alien spouting electricity is raging?!
뭐야, 전기를 내뿜는 우주인이 날뛰고 있다고!?
Dagwon, takeoff!
다그온 발진이다!
Are you joking? I have to clean the restroom by myself?!
에에? 거짓말이지!? 나혼자 화장실 청소!?
Teacher, please understand! I must go!
선생님, 좀 이해해 주세요! 전 가야 한다구요!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Grounded Fire Dagwon
다음회 용자지령 다그온
파이어 다그온 발진 불능
You call that an educational guidance?!
교육적 지도라는 거냐!?
Grounded Fire Dagwon
파이어 다그온 발진 불능